Jeff Brozena

jeff@brozena.net | +1 (570)335-8269

SUMMARY

An operator and teacher with 5+ years in strategic alignment/systems integration, software training, and change management at one of the country's largest privately-held Medicaid pediatric dental groups. With over 50,000 appointments seen per year and little chance for downtime, I stewarded the group from paper-based record-keeping to full digitization, and was entrusted to set strategic direction, improve core business processes and lead complex change shortly before a cross-generational ownership transfer was expected. I leveraged software integration to catalyze systemic organizational change at scale.

EDUCATION Pennsylvania State University

Dec 2019

BS - Information Sciences & Technology

EXPERIENCE

Wellbeing and Health Innovation Lab, College of IST — University Park, PA

Sep 2019 — present

Research Support

 Developing a conceptual and technical framework in Python to detect mental health states using multi-modal data streams reflecting online activities.

The Smilist Management - Great Neck, NY

Feb 2018 — Aug 2018

Manager of Optimization

- Discovered, documented, and re-engineered core business processes at dental service organization containing 20+ locations in the New York metro area.
- Conducted root cause analyses via individual/group interviews after quickly establishing rapport with stakeholders at all levels of management.
- Reduced city and state compliance risk at all sites.
- · Drafted requirements for in-house analytics platform.

Smiles 4 Keeps Pediatric Dentistry — Scranton, PA

Aug 2012 - Nov 2017

Practice Operations

- Transformed one of the country's largest privately-held multi-site dental groups from paper-based, siloed locations to a streamlined, centralized, digitized operation.
- Fostered trust with ownership across several years, served as strategic counsel in technical and non-technical capacities.
- Completed a sequence of practice management software data conversions at all sites, coordinating between internal management and external vendors.
- Identified and voiced the cultural need for standardization across business processes and technical systems, slowly fostering the trust of ownership, management, and hundreds of employees.
- Led a massive initiative to centralize all clinical business operations by consolidating practice management system databases into a single synchronized, usable environment.
- Continued to lead a sequence of employee-facing projects which leveraged the centralized environment for
 continuous improvement, stewarding software development to meet enterprise-level business needs, personally
 training all layers of management and staff.
- Integrated best-of-breed dental analytics platform into daily workflows, creating conditions for legacy understandings to evolve into data-driven decision-making.
- Invited to present to thousands of pediatric dentists at the American Academy of Pediatric Dentistry on the subjects of digitization and compliant record-keeping.

Bedrock Technology — Scranton, PA

Jan 2012 — Aug 2012

Technicia

Penn State University — University Park, PA

Aug 2007 — Dec 2009

Software Trainer

• Promoted to supervisory position in June, 2009.

VOLUNTEERING

Active Minds at Penn State - Founding President

Sep 2010 — May 2011

- Founded Penn State University Park's chapter of the nationwide mental health awareness group Active Minds, Inc.
- Served as a liaison between students and campus mental health support services.
- Designed and prototyped a mobile web application to promote mental health resource utilization on campus.
- Served as a direct point of contact to campus newspapers and other news outlets including the Associated Pressgiving interviews and speaking at length about our mission.

AWARDS

Rock Ethics Stand Up Award, Penn State University

Apr 2011

 ${\bf Emerging\ Scholars\ Fellowship,\ Active\ Minds,\ Inc.}$

Jan 2011

SKILLS

Leadership: Public speaking, Systems thinking, Whole systems management, Written & verbal clarity, Motivational interviewing, Situational leadership

Digital transformation: Software training, Transformational change, Change management, Strategic planning, Business analysis

Healthcare information technology (HIT): HIPAA compliance, Electronic data interchange (EDI), Electronic medical record (EMR), Analytics, SQL, Product management, Systems integration, Software integration, Electronic remittance advice (ERA), Clinical decision support

Program management: Process improvement, Project management, Process optimization, Process management, Lean Six Sigma, Kaizen